# Vincent Villari

Haddon Heights, NJ 08035 VINNYVILLARI@GMAIL.COM (609) 351-2803

Social media savvy, energetic, and successful General Manager with 40+ years of experience in sales, marketing, customer service, inventory and budget building in the hospitality industry. Utilizes a "take ownership" approach to increase profitability and effectively manage staff, expenses and all aspects of the business cycle.

- \*Comprehensive understanding of strategic food and beverage sales.
- \*Expert negotiator with food and beverage vendors.
- \*Educated in wine and spirits
- \*Event Planning.
- \*Profit and Loss statement reconciliation.
- \*Food and Beverage Promotions.
- \*Local store marketing.
- \*Strong communicator.
- \*Leadership ability for over 30 years.

Willing to relocate to: Philadelphia, PA - SOUTH JERSEY - CENTRAL JERSEY Authorized to work in the US for any employer

# Work Experience

### **Restaurant Manager**

Diamond's Restaurant Bar & Catering - Hamilton, NJ October 2017 to Present

diamondsofhamilton.com)

Hamilton, NJ

- Opening experience- Staffing, Hiring, Food inventory, Point of sale set up.
- Food cost and Beverage cost management
- · Scheduling of 40 employees

#### **General Manager**

Spigola Restaurant and Bar - Hamilton, NJ August 2012 to April 2017

Annual Sales Volume: \$2.6 Million

- Increased profitability and customer retention by implementing customer loyalty rewards program, generating 500 accounts within 5 months.
- Motivated and educated sales force with current market product knowledge and sales techniques increasing sales by 15% within 6 months.
- Created strategies to develop and expand existing customer sales, resulting in a 12+% increase in monthly sales.
- Responsible for all day-to-day operations including: hiring, scheduling, training 35 Front-Of-House and Back-Of-House team members and managers, food and liquor inventories, budget and P&L reports,

menu building.

• Developed and deployed all aspects of Catering and Private Events, including Bridal Showers, Funeral

repasts, Communions, and Weddings. Catering contributed 30% of total sales.

• Worked hands-on with scratch kitchen culinary team.

### **General Manager**

Fire Creek Restaurant and Bar - Voorhees, NJ August 2011 to May 2012

Annual Sales Volume: \$2.5 Million

- Hired in as Assistant General Manager
- Promoted to General Manager in 2011
- Responsible for all day-to-day operations including hiring, scheduling, training 50 Front-Of-House and Back-Of-House team members and managers; maintain inventory, ordering, budgets and P&L reports
- Consistently achieved on-time budget and sales goals by working hands-on with teams to improve service standards and highlight scratch fine dining menu.
- Improved guest service and customer loyalty by increasing the training and accountability for employees.
- New restaurant opening from construction, set up floor plan for all stations.
- Created and priced wine lists through tasting, wine knowledge and market shares.
- Install new wine, food and spirits inventory system software and mentored employees on its use.
- Introduced marketing plan and reward program to increase profitability.

### **NJ General Manager**

Scaturro's Restaurant and Bar Marlton July 2007 to August 2011

Annual Sales Volume: \$1.7 Million

- Reduced beverage costs 10% by controlling inventory levels.
- Responsible for all day-to-day operations including hiring, scheduling, training 25 Front-Of-House and Back-Of-House team members and Managers; maintain inventory, ordering, budgets and P&L reports.
- Increased sales year-over-year by working hands-on with team to improve consistency of food quality

and guest service, review and coach regular menu changes, sales techniques.

- Negotiated improved pricing and product quality with vendors to regulate cost and the bottom line.
- Developed and deployed all Banquet menus, handle catering events including booking, deposits, setup

up, and any and all aspects associated with customer service.

#### **General Manager**

Steak & Ale Restaurant - Trevose, PA June 2006 to July 2007

#### **General Manager / Managing Partner**

Concetta's Restaurant and Bar - Trenton, NJ May 2004 to June 2006

# Education

# **Associate of Arts in Restaurant Management**

Paul Smith's College 1978

# Skills

accounting, BUYING/PROCUREMENT, Chef, Excel, inventory

# Additional Information

#### SKILLS:

Chef Tek Food and Beverage Inventory software
Serv-Safe Certified till 2020
Proficient in all accounting and budgetary process
Expert level with P.O.S
Entrepreneurship Spirit
P & L proficient, Opening experience (Fire Creek Restaurant and Bar)
Procurement Experience, Strategies, Negotiate with external vendors.
Finalize purchase details of orders & deliverers
Microsoft Word, Excel and PowerPoint